紙牌屋
前情提要
翻譯   草草
翻譯   肉松
翻譯   國士章魚X
翻譯   杏仁斯嘉麗
翻譯   蘇小黛
翻譯   鹽湖涼開水
時間軸   壬虛浪影
時間軸   萌
后期   餓得慌
顧問   老杜
校對  草草
總監  草草
紙牌屋
人人影視傾情奉獻
第五季  第十一集
安德伍德遭受抨擊
沃克的證詞揭露了不止安德伍德的不法行為
雙城記
查爾斯·狄更斯
今天是你的生日
趁牙齒還在
快微笑一個
莉·哈維  無
莉·哈維  筆記本
凱·杜蘭特  筆記本
馬·厄舍  手機
好
又過生日
活著比死了強
生日快樂
你得做出決定  馬克
You're gonna have to make a decision, Mark.
是為我和克萊爾工作  還是怎么
You wanna work for me and Claire, or not?
我已經聯絡了我自己黨派的人
I have already reached out to members of my own party.
但你還是沒回答我的問題
But you're still not answering my question.
我已經回答了
I think I have.
我可以幫你如愿
I can help you get what you want.
我覺得你知道我的愿望
I think you know what I want.
但你是現在想要  還是四年后要
But do you want it now or in four years?
-拿上這個  -不行
- Take this. - No.
拿著  至少上飛機之前要拿著  好嗎
Come on. At least until you get on the flight, okay?
我撤了
I'm out.
別去見沃克
Don't meet with Walker.
這會提醒他  他最好該怎么做
It'll remind him of his best course of action.
我也曾是美國總統
I was once the President of the United States.
然后總統之位被你偷走了  弗蘭克
You stole the presidency, Frank.
麗薩
Lisa...
她是個隱患  是個癮君子
She's a loose end and an addict.
這兩樣合在一起很糟
That's a bad combination.
我建議我的委托人
I am advising my client
目前行使第五修正案的權利
to plead the Fifth at this time...
其實  我愿意回答議員的問題
Actually, I will answer the congressman's questions.
一定會有出路的  弗蘭西斯
There has to be a way out, Francis.
是嗎
Does there?
加勒特·沃克的證詞非常確鑿
Garrett Walker's testimony couldn't be more damning.
弗蘭西斯·安德伍德是中國資金
Francis Underwood is front and center in a scheme
影響美國選舉的陰謀的罪魁禍首
that had Chinese money influencing an American election.
這是一位聲名狼藉  懷恨在心的前總統的證詞
Testimony from a disgraced and disgruntled former president.
他為什么現在才發聲
Why is he just speaking up now?
你是說他們不應該
Well, are you suggesting that they shouldn't...
重視沃克的話嗎
take what Walker said seriously? I mean...
如果是真的  為什么沉默了那么久
If it's true, why stay silent so long?
一旦事態升級
Which is a question I'm sure
我相信司法委員會一定會問這個問題
the Judiciary Committee will ask once it's up and going.
據我所知  彈劾狀最早會在周末前
My sources say articles of impeachment could be voted on
進行投票表決
as early as the end of the week.
眾議院沒那么有效率
Now as if the House is that efficient.
沃克總統才是該被審查的人
Look, President Walker is the one who should be scrutinized here.
他見人說人話  見鬼說鬼話
He's talking out of both sides of his mouth.
別忘了
And let's not forget,
他過去還有
he has had some emotional problems
-情緒問題  -安德伍德被考慮
- in the past. - Underwood has disrespected
作為國務卿人選之前
the presidency since before he was thought of
-就藐視總統一職  -你被這宣傳攻勢蒙蔽了
- for Secretary of State... - You seem blinded by this crusade.
-當時他還是黨鞭  -你們  等等
- ...when he was nothing more than the House Whip. - You guys, wait.
如果安德伍德被彈劾  那么
If Underwood is impeached, then...
那只是假設  這很危險
That's a hypothetical. It's dangerous.
沒錯
Fair. Well...
湯姆  總統被彈劾后
Tom, where would impeachment leave
副總統克萊爾·安德伍德會怎樣
Vice President Claire Underwood?
進入總統辦公室  當總統
In the Oval, as president.
如果那樣的話
What their arrangement would be,
他們會怎么辦  就難說了
in that case, is anybody's guess.
賽斯  第一夫婦現在情況如何
Seth, what is this like right now for the first couple?
他們在回避這些紛擾
They're avoiding all of this distraction.
他們在繼續為美國人民服務
They're continuing to do the work of the American people.
-黨內警告  -不行
- Censure. - No.
我理解馬克的意思
I see Mark's point.
根本不可能阻止眾議院的共和黨人
There is no way to stop the Republicans in the House.
沃克不是可信的證人
Walker's not a reliable witness.
他的證詞能被核實嗎
Is what he said verifiable?
所以彈劾在所難免
So, impeachment is inevitable.
好吧  那只是假設
Well, that's... that's a presumption.
民主黨掌權的參議院
The Democratic Senate
不會愿意彈劾民主黨總統
will not be inclined to remove a Democratic president.
但他們需要政治掩護
But they need political cover.
黨內警告能滿足他們
Censure will help them with that.
他們可能提出其他的懲罰
I mean, they might propose other penalties,
罰款  譴責聲明
a fine, a statement of condemnation
但他們不會去證實犯罪行為
but they'll stop short of finding criminal wrongdoing.
但如果進展得快  大家都能繼續前進了
And if it happens quickly, everyone can move on.
你倆私下商量過這件事嗎
Did you two get together on this privately?
沒有
No.
弗蘭西斯  這是挽救你第一任期的辦法
Francis, this is one way to salvage your first term.
沃克本該保持沉默的
Walker was supposed to plead the Fifth.
事情出現了意外變化
Well, things took an unexpected turn.
對  他違背了協議
Yes. He went back on his deal,
因為他和自己的證詞一樣不可靠
because he's as pliable as his testimony.
馬克  我不會被眾議院彈劾
Mark, I will not be impeached in the House
那絕對到不了參議院
and it will never get to the Senate.
我們要讓加勒特·沃克名譽掃地
We will destroy Garrett Walker's credibility
這事便會不攻自破
and the case will fall apart.
好吧
Okay.
我能得到豁免權嗎
Can I get immunity?
看你能提供什么信息
Depends on what you give them.
我會聯系副主席
I'll reach out to a ranking member,
但你無法匿名
but you're not gonna get anonymity...
凱茜
Cathy.
-簡  -你好
- Jane. - Hello?
我為你牽腸掛肚  你能相信發生這種事嗎
You've been on my mind. Can you believe what's going on?
抱歉失陪一下
Excuse me for a moment.
就像我母親說的  "簡直是一團亂麻"
As my mother used to say, "It's a red hot mess."
弗蘭克·安德伍德倒霉不代表你也得遭殃
Frank Underwood's demise doesn't have to be yours.
還有許多非營利性
There are non-profits,
民間組織非常希望和你合作
NGOs that would be dying to work with you.
據我所知  我的工作還沒丟
Well, as far as I know, I still have a job.
當然沒有
No, of course.
但誰知道他們接下來會去查誰
But who knows who they'll come after next?
我本來就不是核心圈子的人
I was never part of their inner circle.
你找莫琳很聰明  她是個好律師
You were smart to go with Maureen. She's a good lawyer.
要說誰能幫你全身而退  就是她了
If someone can find you an exit, it's her.
我不會就這么輕易退場的
Well, I'm not gonna go away easily,
所以多謝你的關心  簡
so thank you for your concern, Jane.
我是關心
It is concern.
你認為副總統
do you think the vice president
知道這些事情嗎
had any knowledge of this stuff?
我說了  我真的不知道
Well, as I said, I have no idea.
如果克萊爾挺過這關  成了總統
If... if Claire survives this and becomes president,
那你要怎么辦
where does that leave you?
我好歹也打拼了三十多年  簡
Well, I've been at this for 30 years, Jane,
我想我還是能挺過去的
so I think I can survive.
親愛的  我不是想嚇唬你
Oh, honey, I didn't mean to alarm you.
我也沒害怕
I'm not alarmed.
我只是想說
All I'm trying to say,
我支持你
I'm on your side.
如果是在繼續當總統還是下臺之間選擇的話
If it's the difference in being in office or being out,
我們可以想辦法繞過去
we can work around that.
戴著手銬想辦法吧
Working in handcuffs.
黨內警告是個挫折  但還沒有輸
Censure is a setback. It's not a loss.
你還真是自信滿滿  執拗得很啊
You're very confident and very insistent.
我們會撐過去的  弗蘭西斯
We can come out of this, Francis.
你是說你自己吧
No, you mean you can.
哪怕就一次  你能不能
Can you, for once,
干脆點  接受開價  別再還價了
just take something at face value instead of fighting it?
就好像我過去造的孽能洗清似的
As if I can be washed clean of past sins.
-你認識我多久了  -很久了
- How long have you known me? - Forever.
那你有多了解我
How well do you know me?
就算你克萊爾·安德伍德
How, in your wildest imagination,
再怎么盡情發動想象力
could you, Claire Underwood,
也不該以為我會接受這個
think I would be okay with this?
求你考慮一下吧
Think about it, please.
這關乎我的總統之位
This is the fate of my presidency!
人民想原諒你
The people want to forgive you.
接受吧
Let them.
快點出來  再給我講講
Come out here already. Give me the rest of it.
漢默施密特是個徹頭徹尾的工作狂
Hammerschmidt is a straight-up workaholic.
但是他就快查出什么了
But... he's getting close.
線索慢慢拼湊起來了
Putting the pieces together.
他還查得這么起勁做什么
What's he still grinding so hard for?
看來沃克就要扳倒安德伍德了
Looks like Walker's gonna bring Underwood down.
我不想再談工作了
I don't wanna do this anymore.
佐伊·巴恩斯  瑞秋·波斯納
Zoe Barnes. Rachel Posner.
肖恩  別說了
Sean, please, I...
是我想把他的調查拉回來
I was the one trying to get him back on that.
-結果害得我被解雇了  -能不說這些了嗎
- That's what got me fired. - Can we stop talking about this?
-我的酒呢  -別這樣
- Where's my drink? - Don't do that.
看著我  看我
Look at me. Look.
我這就  不說了
This is me... not talking.
過來  過來
Come here. Come here.
如果有我能幫忙的地方  就告訴我
But if I can be of any help, you let me know.
看我不收拾你
You're gonna get it.
讓我也喝一口
Give me a taste of that.
慢點
Slow down.
靠邊停
Pull over!
你今天騎得很使勁啊  總統先生  還好嗎
You're going pretty hard, Mr. President. You okay?
對于一個命運懸而未決的人來說  夠好的了
Well enough for a man whose fate is hanging in the balance.
不對
No.
你的命運已經定了
Your fate is sealed.
怎么說
Oh, how's that?
你又"預見"到了什么了嗎  艾瑞克
You have a vision for me, Eric?
就算你被彈劾定罪
Even if you're impeached and convicted...
你還是會創造歷史
you still make history.
奧古斯都·安德伍德只是又一個
Augustus Underwood was just another redneck
選錯了立場的農民罷了
who died fighting for the wrong side,
除了你和我沒人記得住他
forgotten by everyone but you and me.
但如果弗蘭西斯·安德伍德下臺了呢
But if Francis Underwood is removed from office?
你的遺產也不會消散
Your legacy won't die.
反而會更加牢固
It'll be solidified.
你會遺臭萬年
You'll be infamous.
政治遺產和遺臭萬年可不是一回事
Legacy and infamy are not the same thing.
你將被人銘記  誰在乎原因呢
You'll be remembered. Who cares why?
我得回去了
I have to get back.
等等  聽我解釋一下
Hold up. Let me explain.
弗蘭西斯
Francis.
Francis?
我說清楚
Just to be clear,
我其實一直都知道你在看著我
it's not that I haven't always known you were there.
只是我對你的情感很復雜
It's that I have mixed feelings about you.
我質疑你的意圖
I question your intentions...
而且我對關注感到矛盾
and I'm ambivalent about attention.
但別當我是針對你
But don't take it personally.
我對每個人的感覺幾乎都是這樣的
It's how I feel about most everybody.
我們怎能相信他說的話呢
How can we trust anything he says?
加勒特·沃克任總統期間一直在用藥
Garrett Walker was medicated while he was in office.
這我們都知道
We all know that.
不  這不是論據  這是事實
No, it's not a talking point. It's the truth.
我們不知道他具體用的什么藥
We don't know exactly what he was taking.
私下說
Off the record...
你能告訴我湯姆·漢默施密特在忙什么嗎
can you tell me what Tom Hammerschmidt's working on?
拜托  你們倆在那兒就沒有交集嗎
Come on, you two don't cross paths over there?
他為了一篇報道聯系過我
He reached out to me on a story.
之后就沒回音了
I never heard back.
好  謝謝
Okay. Thank you.
隨便你相不相信他說的
You can believe what he's saying or not.
但加勒特·沃克在服藥...
But Garrett Walker was taking serious medication...
千萬不要把一個陌生的U盤
Never... never put an unknown flash drive
插在聯網的電腦上  千萬不要
into a networked computer. Never.
你不用一直說這話
You don't have to keep telling me.
-是我叫你來的  記得嗎  -記得
- I called you, remember? - Yeah.
好  看看能糟糕到哪里去
Okay. Do your worst.
好  目前來看都還好
Okay. So far so good.
有東西
There is something.
謝謝
Thank you.
我得掛了
I have to go.
沒事吧
Everything okay?
-現在不方便  -今晚見
- Not now. - See you tonight?
等我忙完了給你打回去
I'll call you when I'm done.
我覺得出現了泄密者
I think there's a leak.
安德伍德政府的
In the Underwood Administration.
不知道
No idea.
不  這話說得有點早
Well, no, that's a little premature.
這不是水門事件  現在還不是
This isn't Watergate... yet.
嗯
Yeah.
好
Okay.
艾力克斯
Alex.
司法委員會是不可能了
So... Judiciary won't be happening for you.
只有零星幾個民主黨人的位置
Just the few slots for Democrats.
都剛被領導層安排了
Leadership just filled those
保守派民主黨人  抱歉
with a couple of old Blue Dogs. Sorry.
有一件事你倒是說對了
Well, you were right about one thing.
加勒特的證詞沒有讓我交到朋友
Garrett's testimony did not make me any friends.
在你們黨不行
Not in your party, no.
今天早晨  我正式成為無黨派議員了
Well, as of this morning, I'm officially an independent.
我覺得共和黨能給我在司法委員會找個差事
I think the GOP can find me a place on judiciary.
-好吧  艾力克斯  -這一步很明智
- Okay, Alex. - It's a good move.
四年后
Four years from now,
我覺得選民們會想要一個局外人的
I think an outsider's what the voter will be looking for.
是啊  未來屬于第三黨候選人
Yeah, third-party candidate is the future,
而且永遠都是
and always will be.
加勒特·沃克為什么改主意了
Why did Garrett Walker change his mind?
不是我讓他改主意的
It wasn't me who made that happen.
我不知道
I don't know.
有時我們不知為何  但事情就發生了
Sometimes things happen without us knowing why.
他們逮捕了一個他們明知清白的人
They arrested someone they knew was innocent.
-斯坎倫州長否認了  -他當然會了
- Governor Scanlon denies it. - Of course he does.
-而國安局無可奉告  -一貫如此
- And the NSA has no comment. - As a rule.
不行  出去
No, out. Get out.
請五分鐘后再來
Five minutes, please.
謝謝
Thank you.
聯調局確認他們逮捕了卡拉比
The FBI confirms that they arrested Kalabi
他正在候審  但僅此而已
and that he's awaiting trial, but that's all.
沒錯  僅此而已
That's right, that's all.
但是有聯調局的探員
But there are agents in the FBI
對此案的處理方式很不滿
who were not happy with the way this went down.
而且沒有一個人允許我們
And not one of them will let us
公開他們的姓名
use their name on the record.
我們無法核實
We can't confirm the story.
湯姆  這么大的事沒有消息源是不能發的
Tom, we can't run a story this big without a source.
-我知道  -本報從來沒這么做過
- No. I know. I know. - This paper has never done that.
-我知道  -誰知道是什么人給你發的
- I know. - Who knows who sent you this?
我知道  我知道
I know. I know.
我需要你幫我放個料出去
I need you to float something out for me.
給頭條網
Give it to Slugline.
你要我怎么說
What do you want me to say?
就說你在辦公室偶然看到
You picked it up here in the office.
雖然沒查實
It's not confirmed...
但似乎值得報道
but it seems like a story.
去印出來吧
Go ahead and print it.
我對你這么做完全不知情
And I had no idea you're doing this.
操  我操  操操操
Fuck! Fuck. Fuck. Fuck.
在我看來
Well, it looks to me like
安德伍德團隊錯誤逮捕了一名
the Underwood campaign had a Muslim visiting the US
訪美穆斯林  就為了
wrongly arrested in order to
能在大選日影響選情
influence the vote on Election Day.
如果你相信這個
And if you believe that,
那你就不得不質疑
then you have to ask some questions
這對田納西州選情的影響有多大
about the impact this had on the results in Tennessee,
當時各方均預計安德伍德總統會輸掉田州
where President Underwood was predicted to lose.
我們都知道哈里發國的威脅是真實的
We all know that ICO is a real threat.
沒人否認這一點  而且我
Nobody is denying that, and I...
今天不要轉接電話進來
No calls get through to me, not today.
如果有媒體問你
And if you get pressed,
就說白宮目前沒有任何評論
the White House has no comment at this time.
好  先生
Yes, sir.
拜托你人走關門
Close the door behind you, please.
這事你知道多少
What do you know about this?
首先  你這么問什么意思
First of all, what are you getting at?
其次  如果我知情的話
And secondly, if I had any information,
我也肯定不會瞞著不報
I wouldn't be keeping it to myself.
賽斯  我就跟你直說了
Seth, I am asking you straight up.
如果你知道什么  現在就告訴我
If you know anything, you tell me now.
-別等我動手去查  -不然呢
- Don't make me find out. - Or what?
你想怎么辦  道格
What are you gonna do, Doug?
拿白宮馬克杯悶死我嗎
You gonna suffocate me with a White House mug?
局面已經失控了
The shit is hitting the fan
如果我們再不趕快動手
and we're all going to be covered in it
就都會被牽連進去
if we don't get to work.
請問  我可以繼續忙了嗎
Now... can I please get back to it?
媽的
Shit.
我們只需要啟動
We're essentially turning on
一臺早已就位的設備
an apparatus that's already in place.
我們會打開音頻接收
We'll enable audio capabilities.
所有電話  電郵和短信
All calls, e-mails, messages
進出白宮的一切通訊
in and out of the White House
都會被監控歸檔
will be monitored and archived.
搜索泄密者期間每通電話都會被錄音
Every phone call will be recorded as we search for the leak.
視頻監控呢
Video surveillance?
我們可以再加裝設備
We can install additional devices,
-可是  -用現成的就行
- but... - We use what's already there.
我們將能夠監視監聽白宮所有職員的
It enables us to look and listen in on every computer
每一臺電腦和手機
and every cell phone of everyone working for us.
我們會成立一個衛星監控辦公室
We'll set up a satellite office
成員僅限我本人和斯坦普先生
limited to Mr. Stamper and myself.
格林助理局長和我
Assistant Director Green and I
會匯報任何有價值的情報
will bring whatever is valuable forward.
我想要直接訪問權
I want direct access.
實時影像
Live streaming.
我向您保證  總統先生
I assure you, Mr. President,
有什么有用內容我們都會呈遞給您
we'll bring you anything of substance.
去吧
Do it.
不用說
And needless to say...
我只向您匯報  先生
I report only to you, sir.
我要知道是誰在坑我
I wanna know who did this to me.
我去查  先生
I'm on it, sir.
你對道格有顧慮嗎
You're having doubts about Doug?
-怎么  你有嗎  -沒有  就是
- Why? Are you? - No, I'm just...
我現在大概質疑一切了
I'm questioning everything, I guess.
這事解決之前
Until this is resolved,
你和我對于我們的言行
you and I should be very careful
要萬分小心了
about what we say or do.
我們的私人需求得放到一邊
And our personal needs have to be put aside.
你了解一些人  認識他們多年
You know people. You know them for years.
而突然  他們就像出現在你廚房里的陌生人
And then... suddenly they're like strangers in your kitchen.
熟悉和陌生只有一線之隔
Familiar can turn foreign on a dime.
-我能做什么嗎  -你可以別妄動
- Is there anything I can do? - You can be quiet.
道格  我可不是泄密者  你知道的
Doug, I am not the leak here. You know that.
-我會再聯系  -別掛
- I'll be in touch. - Don't hang up.
要我列出我為本屆政府
Do I need to make a list of the risks
冒的風險嗎
I've taken for this administration?
都是我從未做過的事
Things I have never done before.
我們當面談吧  好嗎
Let's just talk in person, okay?
誰啊
Yes?
請找莉安·哈維
LeAnn Harvey, please.
-是誰  -聯調局
- Who is it? - FBI.
如果你能想到什么
If you think of anything,
名片最下面是我的手機號
that's my cell at the bottom of the card.
是自殺嗎
Was it a suicide?
槍管抵著他的眼睛
Barrel of the gun was pressed against his eye, so...
你是他的聯系人  他會做出這樣的事嗎
You were his contact. Would he do something like that?
我覺得不會
I don't think so.
或許他沒有
Well, maybe he didn't.
-那槍呢  -問題就在這里
- And the gun? - That's the thing.
不見了
It's not there.
或許是酒店的住客或員工拿走了
Maybe someone staying at the hotel or working there took it.
你們會告知我吧
You'll let me know?
當然
Yeah. Sure.
馬克
Mark...
副總統和我商量了
the vice president and I have discussed it and...
我們接受你的立場了
we've come around to your position.
很好
Very good.
鑒于現在爆出的新聞
Uh, considering the news that's breaking,
恐怕不會那么容易了
it's not going to be quite as easy.
知道消息是哪來的嗎
Any idea where this story came from?
還不知道  但很快就會知道
No, not yet. But I will soon.
我會告訴他們你愿接受黨內警告
I'll let it be known that you're open to censure.
你該知道
And you should be aware.
這并不意外
It's not surprising.
羅梅洛要進入司法委員會了
Romero is moving over to the Judiciary Committee.
他為什么不呢
Well, why wouldn't he?
他想把這事做到底  他還沒放過我呢
He wants to see this through. He's still coming after me.
我猜兩方的領導層都已經受夠他了吧
Well, I imagine leadership from both parties has had enough of him.
嗯  我不想往小了說
Yeah, I don't want to diminish this.
我們在控制損失
We are in damage control.
克萊爾  我覺得
Claire, I think...
或許你最好還是
it might be best for you to
盡量別摻和這事
stay out of this as much as possible.
不  我要維護總統
No, I... I will defend the president.
我覺得最好是
Vice presidential business as usual
副總統一切照舊
is the way to play it, I think.
這事你得相信我的直覺
You need to trust my instincts on this one.
-好  -謝謝  馬克
- Okay. - Thank you, Mark.
謝謝
Thank you.
你可能并不總同意他  但你喜歡他
You may not always agree with him, but you like him.
我喜歡他清醒的頭腦
I like his clarity.
別忘了  他的候選人輸了
Let's just not forget, his candidate lost.
而現在他為你工作
And now he works for you.
不  我覺得他其實在為你工作  不是嗎
No, I think he's really working for you, isn't he?
別疑神疑鬼  弗蘭西斯
Don't get paranoid, Francis.
現在不  更待何時
If not now, when?
你得走了
You have to go.
什么
I what?
你得離開
You need to leave.
發生什么了
What's happened?
這里就是容不下你了
There's just no place for you here anymore.
你考慮過了嗎
Have you been thinking about this?
是的
Yes.
我不同意
I don't agree.
我說得很明白了
I'm completely clear about it.
你可以喝完你的咖啡
You can finish your coffee.
你怎么做到的
How do you do that?
就那樣關閉感情
Just... turn off like that?
走吧  湯姆
Please go, Tom.
走
Go.
好吧
Okay.
如果這是你的選擇
If that's what you choose.
也來點
Join us?
算了  我不想把新肝也喝壞
No, I'm trying not to wear out the new model.
什么事你們大駕光臨
So, to what do I owe this pleasure?
我就直說了  弗蘭克
Well, I'll get right to it, Frank.
眾議院的共和黨人終于有一次
Well, for once, the House Republicans...
能完成工作了
are getting something done.
壞消息是  那就是彈劾你
And the bad news is, is that thing is impeaching you.
我覺得司法委員會
Oh, I think the judiciary
離做出決定還差得遠呢
is a long way from making any sort of decision.
我得知  他們接下來幾天里就會把
They're sending articles of impeachment to the House
彈劾狀送交眾議院
in the next few days, I'm told.
而今早的新聞更是火上澆油
And that news this morning is just adding fuel to the fire.
天吶
Jesus Christ.
我是來問你是否...
And I'm here to ask if you...
你是否能考慮辭職
Would you consider resigning
而不是把這事扯到參議院去
instead of dragging this through the Senate?
你們倆瘋了嗎
Have the two of you lost your minds?
你  泰瑞  你自己也在受調查
And you, Terry, you're under investigation yourself
你還敢跑來跟我說這話
and you dare come here and ask me this?
我經常恨你恨得牙根癢
I've often hated your guts,
但我承認  我會懷念你的
but I have to admit, I'll miss you.
鮑勃  別忘了
Oh, Bob, in case you've forgotten,
參議院是民主黨的
the Senate is Democratic.
-我短時間內不會走人的  -不是你
- I won't be leaving anytime soon. - Oh, not you.
是我  我已經干不動了
Me. I'm getting too old for this.
什么
What?
眾議院離了鮑勃·博奇不得面目全非了
A House without Bob Birch? It will be unrecognizable.
我覺得已經是這樣了  天吶
I feel like it already is. God...
一直都是這么骯臟的嗎
Was it always this dirty?
那不可能
That's impossible.
我們的先輩就要更干凈些嗎
Were the men before us any more moral?
更配得上他們所處的位置
Any more worthy of the power and position
和所擁有的權力嗎
that they had found themselves in?
更有能力為公眾牟利嗎
Any more capable of doing a single goddamn thing for the public?
也是  也不是
Well, yes and no.
歷史總是看上去比實際上要好
History has a way of looking better than it was.
或許莎士比亞是對的
Or perhaps Shakespeare was right.
我們都是瘋子給瞎子帶路
We're all just madmen leading the blind.
李女士  我是白宮的賽斯·格雷森
Ms. Lee. This is Seth Grayson, from the White House.
謝謝你接我的電話
Yeah, thank you for taking my call.
我就是有個問題
I just had a question.
有個記者
There, uh... there was a reporter.
等一下  我查查我的筆記
Give me a second. Let me just check my notes.
叫肖恩·杰弗瑞斯
Name's Sean Jeffries.
對  他在做一篇捐贈名單的報道
Yeah, he's working on a story about the donor list,
就是總統接受移植期間的事
around the time of the president's transplant.
不知你能不能來一趟
I was wondering if you could come in
我們好協調一下回應
and we can coordinate our response.
李女士  我們不希望大家認為
Ms. Lee, we don't want people to think
總統得到了特殊待遇
that the president got preferential treatment.
天吶
Jesus.
你給了我什么啊  麥卡
What the hell did you give me, Mac?
天啊
Jesus.
你給了我什么啊  麥卡
What the hell did you give me, Mac?
我有關于頭條網爆料來源的消息
I had a tip on where that Slugline story came from.
你該打給我的
You should have called me.
那也阻止不了什么
That wouldn't have stopped it.
-你是為這事而來嗎  -不  我有別的消息
- Is that why you're here? - No, I got something else.
說吧
Tell me.
我想跟副總統聊聊
I'd like to talk to the vice president about it.
那不可能
That's not possible.
一切都要經過我
Everything goes through me.
我之前沒機會解釋清楚
Well, I didn't have a chance to explain myself.
太可惜了
That's too bad.
她什么樣
What's she like?
她不忍受愚蠢  也不給人第二次機會
She doesn't suffer fools and she doesn't give second chances.
如果你不能讓我再跟她見面
Well, if you can't get me in to talk to her again,
我會另想辦法
I'll find some other way.
你沖昏頭了
You're in over your head.
要么告訴我你知道什么  要么滾蛋
Tell me what you know or move along.
不
No.
我們沒有  漢默施密特先生
We don't, Mr. Hammerschmidt.
不管你掌握了什么信息
Whatever information you have...
別再打給我了
Don't call me again.
我還擔心我那天晚上說錯話了
I was concerned I was out of line the other night.
或許吧
You might have been.
對不起  我有時候口不擇言
I'm sorry. I don't even know what I'm saying sometimes.
算了
Forget it.
等一下
Hey, hang on a second.
我需要告訴你我的想法
I need to tell you how I'm feeling.
國家需要你  總統先生
The nation needs you, Mr. President.
-我們都需要你  -今天就到這兒吧
- We all need you. - We're done for today.
-不  -不
- No. - No?
不  你為什么不愿聽我想說的話
No. Why don't you want to hear what I'm trying to tell you?
聽著  你...夠了
Listen. You... enough.
我愛你  你得知道
I love you. You need to know that.
-我只是想保護你  -你得冷靜下來
- I'm only here to protect you. - You need to calm down.
你是怎么了  你為什么不愿聽
What's wrong with you? Why don't you wanna hear
-我想說的話  -我沒怎么
- what I'm telling you? - There is nothing wrong with me.
但你得回家了
But you need to go home.
是你找我的  是你叫我來的
You reached out to me. You brought me in. I...
夠了
Enough.
-對不起  -他不在
- I'm sorry. - He's out.
我回頭再來
I'll come back later.
不管是什么  我可以轉交給他
Whatever it is, I can give it to him.
你可以托給我轉交的  道格
You can trust me to hand it over, Doug.
-沒叫你跟蹤湯姆·耶茨啊  -有的
- You weren't directed to follow Tom Yates. - Yes, I was.
總統說要監視每個人
According to the president, everyone needs to be watched.
湯姆都不在這里了
Tom's not even here anymore.
弗蘭西斯叫你跟蹤他的嗎
Francis asked you to follow him?
我擔心一個人
I'm concerned about someone.
勞拉·莫雷蒂
Laura Moretti.
我知道她  和她丈夫的事
I know about her... and her husband.
你的行為是判斷不佳的表現  道格
Your behavior shows poor judgment, Doug,
而且可能連累總統
and could be a liability for the president.
是  女士
Yes, ma'am.
等弗蘭西斯回來把這給他
Give these to Francis when he gets back.
我可以給你拿到豁免權
I can get you immunity.
你只需要講出真話
You just need to tell the truth.
確認沃克的證詞都是真的
Confirm that all of Walker's testimony is true.
你不需要這么做
You don't have to do it.
不  莫琳  我要公開說
No, Maureen, I want this on the record.
你怎么能這么背叛安德伍德夫婦
How dare you betray the Underwoods like this?
我們說完了  議員
We're done here, Congressman.
謝謝你抽時間
Well, thank you for your time.
請你準備好
So you're prepared,
司法委員會很快會簽發傳票
a subpoena will be coming soon from the Judiciary Committee.
國務卿女士
Madam Secretary.
你想進去嗎
Do you wanna come in?
是我導致了你丈夫的死
I'm the reason your husband's dead.
我逼迫衛生和人類服務部部長
I forced the Secretary of Health and Human Services...
把弗蘭西斯·安德伍德插在捐贈名單上他之前
to put Francis Underwood in front of him on the donor list.
如果你覺得我是禽獸我也能理解
I understand if you think I'm a monster.
但我不后悔
But I'd do it again.
為了救總統  我愿不惜一切
To save the president, I'd do anything.
你真覺得我不知道嗎  道格
You really think that I didn't know, Doug?
是時機暴露了
The timing gave it away.
來吧  快進屋
Come on. Come on in.
你以為是怎么回事
What did you think was going on here?
我操你不是因為我喜歡你
I'm not fucking you because I like you.
我操你是因為我恨你
I'm fucking you because I hate you.
出去
Get out.
滾出我的車
Get out of my car.
快滾出我的車
Get the fuck out of my car.
滾
Get out!
麥卡倫給了你什么
What did Macallan give you?
-我不知道你在說什么  -我聽見你說話了
- I don't know what you're talking about. - I heard you.
他給了你什么東西
You got something from him.
什么叫"你聽見我說話了"
What do you mean you heard me?
你還在監視我嗎
Were you watching me, too?
他是你什么人
Who was he to you?
喝一杯嗎
Want a drink?
我不喝酒
I don't drink.
對了
Oh, right.
我和他睡過
I was with him.
我還年輕  不該跟他睡的時候
When I was young and shouldn't have been with him.
你喜歡什么  道格
What gets you off, Doug?
有嗎
Anything?
要是麥卡倫給了你什么  我們應該上交
If Macallan gave you something, we should hand it over.
你喜歡嗎
Did you like it?
什么
What?
監視我
Watching me.
喜歡
Yes.
你喜歡你看見的嗎
You liked what you saw?
這是你來找我的原因嗎
That why you came here?
那好吧
Well, then.
我要去健身房  跑步消解壓力
Going to the gym. Run off some of this stress.
你的教練呢
Where's your trainer?
他有一段時間都不會來了
Oh, he won't be coming around for a while.
他有個表情我可不會懷念
He did have a facial expression I won't miss.
是嗎
Is that so?
那種凝固的笑  很瘆人
Sort of perma-smile. It was creepy.
也許他只是開心罷了
Maybe he's just happy.
我不擔心開心
Happiness isn't my concern.
現在不  從來都不
Not now, not ever.
這局面太不幸了  克萊爾
It's a tragic situation, Claire.
-我知道  -我可以給你看看正在發生的事
- I know. - I could show you what's happening.
我看過照片了
I've seen the images.
務必要讓民眾知道霍姆斯城正在發生什么
It's important people know what's going on in Homs.
你改主意了嗎
Are you having second thoughts?
只是現在時機還不到
It's just the timing isn't right yet.
因為你丈夫得不到支持
Because your husband doesn't have the support.
我們得有理有據
We need to make a case.
你做聲明之前  讓全世界做好準備
Prepare the world for when you make a statement.
我認為弗蘭西斯得來做主導
I think Francis needs to be front and center on this.
你沒查到麥卡倫告訴佩特羅夫什么了
You never found out what Macallan told Petrov?
我的線人說  他沒說什么真正有用的
My sources say he never gave him anything concrete.
-他給了莉安一些東西  -我們希望如此
- Well, he gave LeAnn something. - Well, that was our hope.
也許是時候再把她請回來了
Maybe it's time to invite her back in.
也許吧  我得上樓了
Maybe. I need to get back upstairs.
下次在我辦公室見
The next time we meet will be in my office.
我不覺得你丈夫該做主導
I... I don't think your husband should be front and center.
應該是你
I think it should be you.
我沒問你的意見
I didn't ask you what you think.
你得有所準備  克萊爾
You need to be armed, Claire.
無論他怎樣
It's important that you can walk away
你務必得能全身而退
from anything that happens to him.
去他們的
They can kiss my ass.
參議員韋斯特維爾特有意要我
I got an offer from Senator Westervelt.
我也在找
I'm looking, too.
但想下這艘船越來越困難了
But it's getting harder and harder to get off this ship.
我妻子在哪
Where is my wife?
她去哪了
Where has she gone?
如果她是你妻子  你不會想知道嗎
If she was your wife, wouldn't you wonder?
好  安德伍德夫人
Yes, Mrs. Underwood.
別擔心  這事沒發生過
Don't worry. This never happened.
不用你告訴我
You don't have to tell me.
-道格  -該死
- Doug. - Shit.
我該過去嗎
Should I come in?
不  除非你把你手里的東西給我
No. Not until you give me what you've got.
總統先生
Mr. President.
"一位白宮內部人士透露
"A source deep within the White House...
安德伍德總統確實
confirms President Underwood
曾利用可疑情報
used questionable intelligence
為關閉投票中心找理由
to justify voting center closures,
從而使選舉陷入了混亂"
which threw the election into chaos."
你覺得會是誰
Who do you think it is?
可能是格林
Green, probably.
-我們高估了他的忠誠  -我明白了
- We overestimated his loyalty. - I see.
要不
I mean...
還能是誰
who else could it be?
我能做些什么
How can I help?
我們得自救
We need to save ourselves here.
-這事對我倆都很不利  凱茜  -我明白
- It's as much your head as mine, Cathy. - I understand.
我需要你編寫額外的材料
I need you to create additional documents
為追捕卡拉比找理由
that justify going after Kalabi.
制造書面痕跡來支撐我們
A paper trail that will support our actions
選舉日在田納西采取的行動
that we took on Election Day in Tennessee.
我不確定
I'm not sure...
該是什么樣的材料
what those documents would be.
可你夠聰明  對吧  凱茜
Well, but you're smart, Cathy, aren't you?
你會想到的
I mean, you can figure it out.
讓我看看你有多聰明吧
Why don't you just show me how smart you are.
-當然  總統先生  -還有在聯合國的演講
- Of course, Mr. President. - And the presentation at the UN.
-關于敘利亞的  -必須進行
- With Syria? - It needs to happen.
-好吧  -可能會引起非議
- Very well. - There's a possibility of talks,
但我們得讓所有相關方重新回到談判桌上
but we need to get all the interested parties back to the table.
當然
Of course.
你是個好外交官  凱茜
You're a good diplomat, Cathy.
謝謝  總統先生
Thank you, Mr. President.
另外  克萊爾呢
And where is Claire?
她現在需要保持些距離
She needed a little distance right now.
直到我們看清我到底怎么回事
Till we find out what's happening with me.
所以我現在必須指望你了  凱茜
That's why I need to rely on you, Cathy. Now.
很高興你這么想  弗蘭西斯
Well, I'm glad you feel that way, Francis.
是我  我可以見面了
Yes. I'm ready to meet.
我現在就要見面  馬上
I wanna meet now. Right now.
在一次
After a tumultuous election,
前所未有的混亂選舉后
the likes of which have never been seen,
美國面臨著更多的問題
America faces more questions...
我現在一堆破事  沒時間應付你
Shit is insane right now. I don't have any more time for you.
如果最近從白宮泄露出來的情報
If the recent leaks coming out of the White House
得到證實  總統將面臨...
prove to be true, the president could face...
白宮身份牌  你從哪弄的
A White House ID? Where did you get that?
我還以為是你給的
I thought this came from you.
你說什么呢
What the hell are you talking about?
-我現在是副新聞發言人了  -去你媽的
- I'm deputy press secretary. - The fuck you are.
我接到了副總統辦公室的電話
I got a call from the vice president's office,
讓我過來
asking me to come in.
我到的時候  這個已經準備好了
And when I got here, this was waiting for me.
我剛才一小時都在辦手續
I just spent the last hour doing my paperwork.
我沒時間跟你胡扯
I don't have time for this.
加勒特·沃克總統的爆炸性證詞
President Garrett Walker's bombshell testimony, which...
我有國務卿杜蘭特的辭職信
I have Secretary Durant's resignation.
我相信她就是泄密者
I believe she was the leak,
并且可能要為
and might have to take responsibility
選舉當晚發生的事負責
for whatever happened on election night.
先生  司法委員會現在隨時
Sir, the judiciary could issue a resolution
會發出彈劾決議了
for impeachment any day now.
我們得現實地面對這事對總統的傷害
We need to be realistic about damage to the president
即便參議院不定罪
even if the Senate doesn't convict.
你承諾的是黨內警告
You promised us censure.
杜蘭特的泄密已經起到同樣的效果了  不是嗎
Well, Durant's leak took care of that, didn't it?
我們有個應對參議院的計劃
So, we have a plan for the Senate.
我建議重點保護副總統
I suggest we work on protecting the vice president.
確保她在整個過程中能全身而退
Make sure she exits this whole process unscathed.
我們要怎么才能做到
And how do we do that?
聲稱不知情  副總統沒審閱任何相關信息
Plead ignorance. The vice president wasn't read into anything.
什么也不知道
Didn't know anything.
-也什么都沒做  -不行的
- Didn't do anything. - That won't play.
她會看上去不知情  但人們知道并非如此
She'll look uninformed, and the people know she isn't.
距離會讓她看起來無辜
Oh, the distance will help her look innocent.
無辜或有罪  有能力或沒用  不管怎樣
Innocent, guilty, capable, incompetent, whatever it is...
公眾都會往反方向想
the public is going to think the opposite.
所以真是怎么都輸
So, really there is no winning.
照你的意思來吧
Whatever you think is best.
如果我被判無罪  你會有四年時間
You're gonna have four years to prove yourself
在位子上證明自己  希望是八年
on the inside if I'm acquitted. Hopefully, eight.
但如果我被判有罪呢
But what happens if I'm not acquitted?
我們現在不用考慮那個
We don't have to deal with that right now.
不  我想聽到一個計劃
No, I want to hear a plan.
這正是找你來的原因
That's why you're here.
給我冷冰冰  硬梆梆的事實
To give me the cold, hard facts.
我的盤算不比您高明  總統先生
Oh, your calculus is as good as mine, Mr. President.
根本沒有計劃
There is no plan.
只能拖住司法委員會  穩住參議院
Except slow down judiciary, secure the Senate.
我擔心一個人
I'm concerned about someone.
勞拉·莫雷蒂
Laura Moretti.
為什么把這個也放進來
Why did you include this?
你跟克萊爾談這個什么勞拉·莫雷蒂
You and Claire talking about a Laura Moretti?
我想讓你知道  先生  她知道了
I wanted you to know, sir, that she knows.
我在名單上幫你插了隊
I jumped you on the list.
好獲得肝臟捐贈
To receive a donor liver.
我強迫衛生和人類服務部部長調高了你的排名
I forced the HHS Secretary to move you up.
-那不可能  -我威脅了她  先生
- That's not possible. - I threatened her, sir.
這是前所未有的道德違規  但我不后悔這樣做
It was an unprecedented ethical violation. But I don't regret it.
我獨守這個秘密  好讓你...
I kept it to myself, so that you would...
在有人發現時可以合理推諉
have plausible deniability if anyone found out.
我也沒告訴安德伍德夫人
I didn't tell Mrs. Underwood either.
她是從別處知道的
She learned another way.
她知道卻沒告訴我
She knew and didn't tell me.
看起來是這樣
Seems so.
她對耶茨的監控反應如何
And how did she react to the Yates surveillance?
那個她怎么說的
What did she say about that?
她沒對我表達她的感受  先生
She didn't show her feelings to me, sir.
你救了我的命
You saved my life.
我與你同在  先生
I'm here for you, sir.
直到永遠
Always.
你對安德伍德夫人有疑慮嗎
Do you have concerns about Mrs. Underwood?
-你有嗎  -我永遠不會這樣講
- Do you? - I would never say that.
我要給你看點東西
I want to show you something.
有45分鐘我不清楚她的行蹤
There's 45 minutes where I can't account for her whereabouts.
我不知道她去了哪里  見了什么人
I don't know where she went or who she saw.
但是她對我說謊了
But she lied to me.
我認為你應該休息一下  先生
I, uh... I think you should get some rest, sir.
總統沒有讓我審閱
The president didn't read me in.
我不在房間里
I wasn't in the room.
總統沒有讓我審閱
The president didn't read me in.
我不在房間里
I wasn't in the room.
我對此毫不知情
I didn't know anything about it.
總統沒有讓我審閱
The president didn't read me in.
我不在房間里
I wasn't in the room.
我對此毫不知情
I didn't know anything about it.
怎么樣  弗蘭西斯
How's that, Francis?
最新消息  國務卿凱瑟琳·杜蘭特
This is just in. Secretary of State Catherine Durant
將在眾議院司法委員會作證
to appear in front of the House Judiciary Committee.
這個意外令已經非常戲劇化的...
This comes as yet another surprise in the already dramatic...
-什么時候收到的  -不久之前
- When did it come in? - A short while ago.
不是凱茜·杜蘭特
It's not Cathy Durant.
我們能確定嗎
Are we sure?
她爭取了豁免權
She negotiated immunity.
她作證時
And she's going on record
將公開她知道的一切
with everything she knows when she testifies.
我們知道是誰嗎
Do we have any idea?
不知道
No.
好
Good.
謝謝
Thanks.
特朗普上任后一直麻煩不斷  不僅一系列政策遭到媒體的廣泛批評
還有多個國會委員會在對俄羅斯干擾2016大選進行調查
在前聯調局局長科米被突然撤職后  媒體普遍認為特朗普干預司法
許多媒體開始討論是否應該彈劾他  但也有冷靜的聲音指出
目前特朗普所屬的共和黨在參眾兩院都占多數  彈劾基本無可能
當年比爾·克林頓因為在萊溫斯基事件上公然說謊  國會啟動彈劾程序
眾議院投票表決同意彈劾后  彈劾的決議在參議院沒有獲得足夠票數
在參眾兩院的兩次投票中  克林頓所屬的民主黨黨員大都堅定地站在總統這邊
目前批評特朗普的聲浪雖高  但都是來自民主黨
而即便在特朗普的一些言行明顯離譜  甚至有違法嫌疑的情況下
國會共和黨也不敢對他有太多微辭  所以媒體才認為目前彈劾可能性很小
可以看出  涉及到彈劾時  美國兩黨議員
基本都是根據自己的黨派歸屬來決定立場的